Guide to the Elaine D. Engst papers, 1979-2015.
Engst, Elaine D. papers
- New York Historical Documents Inventory (HDI) Procedures Manual, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- "Brooklyn Historical Society and the New York Historical Documents Inventory, 1985-2007," by Marilyn H. Pettit, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- History 4850 Immigration Interview Release and Distribution Forms, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Non-Book Materials and Manuscripts Listings in the History of Science Collection for Re-Boxing and Re-Housing, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Cornell Dissertation and New York Times Index of Frank Holt/Erich Muenter, 1914-1915 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- The Homes Economics Archive and the College of Human Ecology
  - The College of Human Ecology's Centennial Exhibit and Professor Joan Jacobs Brumberg's "HD 455: Archival Research: Exploring the History of Home Economics", 2000 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Martha Van Rensselaer Nomination for the National Women's Hall of Fame, 1955, 1995, 2002, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economics in the Twentieth Century" Conference, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Re-Housing and Digitization of the Oscar of the Waldorf Menu Collection, 1993, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Digitization of the Icelandic and Faroese Photographs of Frederick W. W. Howell, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Biographical Information on David "Davy" Fletcher Hoy, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Cornell News Service and Other Cornell Humor, 1999-2000, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Re-Housing and Cataloging Proposal for the Native American Collection of the Huntington Free Library, 1999, 2004, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Save America's Treasures Grant Proposal for the Native American Collection of the Huntington Free Library, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Digitization of the George Hyde Clarke Family Papers, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- The Fiske Icelandic Collection
  - General Information and Loan Agreements for the "Living and Reliving the Icelandic Sagas" Travelling Exhibition, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Panel and Catalogue Texts and the American-Scandinavian Foundation Grant Proposal from the Library of Congress for the "Living and Reliving the Icelandic Sagas" Travelling Exhibition, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - National Endowment of the Humanities Grant Proposal for the "Living and Reliving the Icelandic Sagas" Travelling Exhibition, 1999, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Organization and Items Listing for the "Living and Reliving the Icelandic Sagas" Travelling Exhibition, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - List of Invitations for the "Living and Reliving the Icelandic Sagas" Travelling Exhibition at the Library of Congress, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Brochures for the "Living and Reliving the Icelandic Sagas" Travelling Exhibition, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Contract with Bruccoli Clark Layman for Icelandic Writers, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Exhibit Plan for "West-Viking: The North Atlantic Saga", 1998, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Digitization and Preservation Project Proposal for the Fiske Icelandic Collection to the National Endowment of the Humanities, 1993, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Re-Housing and Bar-Coding of the Fiske Icelandic Collection, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - On the Publication of Islandica, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
  - Miscellany Related to the Fiske Icelandic Collection and Icelandic Collections at Other Institutions, 1912, 2000-2002 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Drafts of "Baseball, True Crime, the FBI and I(LL): Interlibrary Loan for Archival Collections Revisited" Presentation and the Association of College and Research Libraries (ACRL) Loan Guidelines, 2009, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Image Collection Implementers' Workshop and "Reformatting Images for Preservation and Digitizing Images at Cornell University" Presentation, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Schedule for the Inauguration of Hunter R. Rawlings III and Related Exhibit Cases, 1995, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Data Entry for the Interlaken Newspaper Index, 1981, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- International Dictionary of Library Histories, 1973, 1980, 1986, 1988-1989, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Early International Students and Lists of Japanese, Latin American, and Puerto Rican Students at Cornell University (Includes photocopies), 1873, 1904, [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 53-56)
- Drafts of Finding Aids for the Ithaca College Study Center for Early Religious Life in Western New York, 1978, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- On the Accessibility of the Laura Riding Jackson and Schuyler B. Jackson Collection and Related Correspondence, 1969, 1977, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Correspondence of the Board of Literary Management of the Late Laura (Riding) Jackson, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Jewish Life at Cornell University
  - Miscellaneous News Articles, Correspondence, and Histories on Early Jewish Student Life at Cornell University (Includes photocopies), 1873, 1913, 1915, 1925, 1927, 1932-1933, 1955, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous News Articles and Cornell Publications on Early Jewish Student Life at Cornell University, 1906, 1932, 1945, 1957, 1973, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence on the B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations, 1948, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Articles on Jewish Students and Higher Education, 1919, 1971, 1982, 1988, 2003, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous Publications on Jewish Student Life at Cornell University and Drafts of "Jewish Life at Cornell, 1865-2005," with Bibliographic Citations, 1930, 1966, 1981, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Jewish Life at Cornell, 1865-2005," Presentation with the Cornell Hillel Foundation, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Issues of Kolenu: Cornell's Jewish Student Publication, 1974-1980, 1983-1984, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Harold I. Saperstein: The Cornell Experience" Presentation, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Funeral Program and Miscellaneous Writings of Margaret Mary Donohue "Peggy" John, 1990, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- The Johnson Family Papers
  - Correspondence on the Accessibility of the Johnson Family Papers, 1995-1996, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Johnson Family Papers Presentation, [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence with Sarah L. Johnson Concerning the Donation of the Johnson Family Papers, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Finding Aids for Alexander Bryan Johnson Collections, 1975, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Press Release and Related Items on the Donation of the Johnson Family Papers (Includes photocopies), 1814, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Letter from Cleveland M. Jones (Includes photocopies), 1870, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- "How the Robert Trent Jones Papers Came to Cornell University" Article, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Newspaper Clippings on Robert Trent Jones, 2010, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- "Greeting to Cornell on the Hundredth Anniversary of Ezra Cornell's Birthday," by David Starr Jordan, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Letter from Stephen Joyce on the "Post-Industrial Joyce" Conference, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Dispatch News Service International Records in the Swarthmore College Peace Collection on Behalf of George McTurnan Kahin, 1974, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, Newspaper Articles on, and Miscellaneous Writings of Carol Kammen, 2000, 2002-2004, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Articles of Publication for "Part and Apart: The Black Experience at Cornell, 1865-1945," by Carol Kammen, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Furthermore Grants in Publishing Application for Carol Kammen, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Lee B. Kass Papers, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Bill Kay and Samuel L. Hirshland Dedication Ceremony, 1992, 1995, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
- "Regardless of Sex or Color" Kendal Presentation, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- George S. Kephart Family Papers, 1951, 1972, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Kirtas Digitization Services, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Kodak Library Image Consortium Collaboration, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Building Plans for Carl A. Kroch Library, c. 1992 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Report on Vault Space Availability, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Carl A. Kroch Library Dedication, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- The Marquis de Lafayette Collection
  - Photocopy of Letter from Anastasie de Lafayette to General George Washington, 1784 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Finding Aid for the Arthur H. and Mary Marden Dean Lafayette Collection, 1520-1849, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "Lafayette: Citizen of Two Worlds" Exhibit Planning, 2006, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Biographical Articles on the Marquis de Lafayette, 1970, 1972, 1977, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Life Mask of the Marquis de Lafayette, 1966, 1976, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Lambda Alpha International Archives, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Archival Holdings and Case Descriptions for the Landscape Architecture Exhibit, [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 44-45)
- Latin American and Hispanic Manuscripts Project with a List of Cornell's Archival Holdings, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 46-47)
- Preservation and Digitization of the Lavoisier Manuscript Collection, 1962-1963, 1981, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Institute of Museum and Library Services (IMLS) Grant Application for the Lavoisier Manuscript Collection, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 49-50)
- List of the Cornell University Law School's Archival Holdings, [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Bruce Lewenstein's "Public Perceptions and Constructions of the Y2K Problem" Project, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- The Jack Lewis Collection, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- "Cornell University Library History" Presentation, 1999, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Future Plans for the Cornell University Library, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Jon Lindseth Donations, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Matt Lyons' Notes on Azriel Bibliowicz's Interview with Rose Goldsen, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- Digitization of the George Macartney, 1st Earl Macartney Mission to China Manuscripts, 1917, 2001, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 58-59)
- National Endowments for the Humanities (NEH) Grant Application for the Maeda Ai Collection, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Obituaries for Rowena Morse Mann, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 61)
- John Marcham's Class of '50 Archive, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 62)
- MAS2010 Project Reports, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Michael A. McCarthy Papers Proposal, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 64)
- Acknowledgements on Donations of Michael A. McCarthy Papers Finding Aids, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Memorandums, Correspondences, and Organization of the Michael A. McCarthy Papers, 1997-1999, 2001, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 66-68)
- Memorial to Eamon McEneaney and Publication of "A Bend in the Road", 2004-2005, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 69)
- McGraw Tower
  - McGraw Tower Restoration Project, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - McGraw Tower Chimes Rededication Planning and Program, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of McGraw Tower Chimes Records, 1869, 1907-1909, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Official Report on the McGraw Tower Pumpkin, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with Fred W. McLafferty, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Articles on the John McMullen House, 1987-1988, 1994, 1997, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Richard Meier and Articles on the History of Modern Architecture, 1998, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Library of Congress/Ameritech Grant Application for the Oscar of the Waldorf Digital Menu Collection, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Museum Educational Site Licensing (MESL) Project, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Museum Educational Site Licensing (MESL) Project Technical Report, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Migrant Agricultural Workers in New York State: A Documentary Survey
  - Documentary Heritage Program (DHP) Grant Application for the Migrant Agricultural Workers in New York State Project, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Reports and Correspondence on the Migrant Agricultural Workers in New York State Project, 1992, 1998-1999, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Migrant Farmworkers Records in Upstate New York Survey and Guide and Documentary Heritage Program (DHP) Grant Extension, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Board of Cooperative Educational Services (BOCES) Geneseo Migrant Center Visit, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- The John S. Minton Punchboard Collection, 1997-1999, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
- The Making of America (MOA) Project and the Stevens Family Papers, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Edward Stokes' Survey of the Hedda Morrison Collection Negatives, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Two Magazine Articles on Toni Morrison, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Policy on Museum Acquisitions, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- List of Johnson Museum of Art Collections, [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Original Introduction to the William I. Myers Papers, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Naiad Press Purchase, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Correspondence with Dmitri Nabokov, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Chronology of New York State History from 1609 to 1940, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- New York Heritage Documentation Program and Rediscovering New York History and Culture, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Foundation of the New York State Nurses Association Inc., 1987, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) Fellowship, 1989, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- The John Nolen Papers and Research Fund
  - John Nolen Research Fund Grant Applications, 1998-2001, 2006, 2008-2009, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 30-36)
  - Save America's Treasures (SAT) Grant Application for the John Nolen Papers, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Barbara Nolen Strong's Last Will and Petition for Probate of Will, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Digitization of the John Nolen Papers, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - John Nolen Papers Re-Organization and Preservation Project, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Older Persons Record (OPR) Index Guidelines, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- "Beautiful Birds: Masterpieces from the Hill Ornithology Collection" Exhibit and Its Website, 1986, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- "Paper, Leather, Clay, and Stone: The Written Word Materialized" Exhibit, 1995, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 43)
- William "Bill" Phillips' Donation of Heinrich Harrer's Seven Years in Tibet, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Organization and Cataloging of Photography, 1980, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Archives Photograph Collection, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  Folder Titled "Micro TV"
- "Possibilities for a Photograph Database" and a Report by Adam Engst, 1987, 1989, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 47-48)
- Albert Podell's Film and Photo Collection Project, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Institute of Museum and Library Services (IMLS) Grant Application for the Preservation and Digitization of Political Americana Collections, 1999-2002 (Box 6, Folder 50-52)
- Library of Congress/Ameritech Grant Application for the Susan H. Douglas Collection of Political Americana, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Report on the Cornell University Collection of Political Americana Digitization Project, 2000, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Plaques and Sculptures, [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Physics and Scientific Collections at Cornell University (Includes photocopies), 1888, 1915, 1958, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Cornell University President's and Provost's Office Project
  - Cornell Presidential Papers Project, 1974, 1981, 1988-1990, 1994, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 57-58)
  - Access Systems Records Management Analysis of the Cornell President's and Provost's Office Project, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Cornell University President's and Provost's Office Project Report, 2005, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Letter to a Freshman from Frank H. T. Rhodes, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Processing Guidelines, 1973, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 62-63)
- Annotated Bibliography on Progressive Cities and a Draft of a Proposal for the Supporting Effective Educator Development (SEED) Grant Program, 1987, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- Proposal to the Clarence S. Stein Institute to Support Publication of Activists in City Hall: The Progressive Response to the Reagan Era in Boston and Chicago by Pierre Clavel, 1986, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- The Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning 1969-2005 Collection, 2005-2007 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Prospective Collections, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- The William B. Provine Collection on Evolutionary Biology, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 68)
- Provenance of Two Psi Upsilon Chairs, 1963, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 69)
- Paleontological Research Institute Cataloging Project, 2001, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 70-71)
- "Centennial of Psychology at Cornell 1891-1991" Exhibit, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 72)
- Quaker History and the Founding of Cornell University, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- "The Search for the Quaker College," by Thomas D. Hamm, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- First Four Reports of the Collection of Regional History at Cornell University, c.1942, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR) Survey of Recorded Sound, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with Helen "Happy" Reichert, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- List of Republican Party Collections, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Republican/Conservative Foundations and a Letter from Rick Perlstein, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Administrative Office Records Restrictions, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- The Reuleaux Collection of Mechanisms, 1999, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant Proposal for the Research Libraries Group's (RLG) Archives, Manuscripts, and Special Collections Retrospective Conversion Project, 1977, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
- Reports on the Research Libraries Group's (RLG) Archives, Manuscripts, and Special Collections Retrospective Conversion Project, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Record Reports System (RRS) Sample Print-Outs, 1982-1983, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
- Research Libraries Information Network (RLIN) Search Card Manual, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections Archival Guidelines and Miscellany
  - Functions and Activities Guidelines, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Intradepartmental Suggestions, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Strategic Planning Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Records Management Guidelines and Related Articles, 1910, 1991-1992, 1995, 1997, 1999-2000, 2004, 2008, [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 19-21)
  - Brochures on Archival Documentation, 1995, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Peter G. Robbins Donation, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Carl Sagan Papers and Proposal for the Carl Sagan Center for the Public Understanding of Science, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Sage Hall Cornerstone Dedication Ceremony (Includes photocopies), 1873, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  Includes 13 Color Photographs of Excavation
- Newspaper Articles on the Sage Hall Cornerstone Dedication Ceremony, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- "An Institution Where Any Person ...: The Origins of Coeducation at Cornell University" Talk for Sage Hall Cornerstone Dedication Ceremony (Includes photocopies), 1857, 1862, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- "The Sartre Disaster" and the University Lectures Committee Meetings Minutes, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Preliminary List of Science Collections, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- September 11th, 2001, Emergency System Messages, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- "150 Ways to Say Cornell: A Sesquicentennial Exhibition"
  - Welcome Presentation for the "150 Ways to Say Cornell" Exhibit, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - "150 Ways to Say Cornell" Exhibit Timeline and Planning Notes, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
  - Two Issues of The Trojan Horse and Items on Cornell United Religious Work, 1954, 1960, 1963, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Centennial Celebration Programs, Speeches, and Newspaper Articles, 1960, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Items on Ezra Cornell's Genealogy, 2012-2014 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Items on the Morrill Land-Grant Act, 1962, 2000, 2012, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Cornell University Library's Seven-Millionth Volume, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Ellen McGowan Biddle Shipman Papers
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant Application for the Ellen Shipman Digitization Project, 2008-2010 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Save America's Treasures (SAT) Grant Application for the Ellen Shipman Preservation and Digitization Project, 2000, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Digitization of the Ellen Shipman Papers for the Whole Discipline Preservation Project, 1994, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Condition Reports for Loans for "The Gardens of Ellen Biddle Shipman", 1996, 1998-1999, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Articles on "The Gardens of Ellen Biddle Shipman" Exhibit at the Library of American Landscape History, Inc., 1996-1997, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Slavic and Eastern European Data Archive Proposal, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Social Networks and Archival Context (SNAC) Research and Demonstration Project, 2009, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Loan Agreement to Geri E. Solomon at Hofstra University for the "Redefining Suburban Studies: Searching for a New Paradigm" Conference and Exhibit, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Col. John James Speed, Jr. Manuscripts, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Social Science Research Council (SSRC) Grant Proposal for the Indochina Studies Program, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Planning for the Clarence S. Stein Exhibit, c. 1986 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Clarence S. Stein Institute Grant Proposal for Professor Kermit Carlyle Parsons Papers, 2009-2010 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Correspondence with Robert C. Stevens about and Processing Work for the Stevens Family Papers, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Ed Stokes' Collaboration with The Photographic Heritage Foundation (TPHF) and the Hong Kong Conservation Photography (HKCP) Foundation, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Clarence S. Stein Research Proposal by Sally Sims Stokes, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Willard D. Straight and Dorothy Whitney Straight Elmhirst
  - Willard and Dorothy Straight, the Dartington Hall Archive and the India House (One Hanover Square) Collection, 1997, 2000, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Drafts and Work Notes for the Guide to the Graphic Materials in the Willard D. Straight Papers, 1980, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Drafts of the Guide to the Microfilm Editions of the Willard D. Straight and Dorothy Whitney Straight Elmhirst Papers, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Visual Documentation in the Willard D. Straight Papers", 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Letter from Margaret Stocker of the India House Foundation on the Willard D. Straight and Dorothy Whitney Straight Elmhirst Papers, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Willard D. Straight and General William J. "Wild Bill" Donovan, 1901, 1952, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Proposal to Archive the William Stringfellow Papers, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- William Strunk Jr. and E. B. White's The Elements of Style Turns Fifty, 1957-1960 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- List of Student Organizations' Collections, [n.d.] (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Enhancing Subject Access, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- The State University of New York's (SUNY) 60th Anniversary Scholarly Conference and a Survey Report on the SUNY Archives, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Includes a Lapel Pin with the SUNY Seal from the Conference
- Quotations for Harold Tanner, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Teaching American History Grant (TAHG) Application for the Spencer-Van Etten Central Schools, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Technical Services Guidelines for Processing Special Media, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Technical Services (Updated) Guidelines, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous Sarah Thomas Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Timbuktu Heritage Project, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Time Capsule Designs, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- The Arnold B. '44 and Gloria Tofias Cornell Librarian's Discretionary Fund, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Two Letters about Mark Twain, 1986, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Portraits, Paintings and Busts in Uris Library, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- "The Launching of the United States National Student Association, 1946-1952", 2000 (Box 8, Folder 23)